<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
    <text>UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
        T1IK BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COM?
        PLETED AND IN OPERATION.
        A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
        TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
        TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
        The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
        of whli h has Ju il b ?? >a op? n? -i for at rvlce.
        
        BOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE PUBLIC GARDEN.
        , ?nly stations in use underground are at the cor
        ? ner of Boylston and Tremont sts. ami at Park-st
        A temporary loop at the latter point permits
        the northbound cars to return without switch?
        ing. When the subway is completed, however.
        there uiii i.ther stations at Si o lay Square,
        Adams Square and Hay market Square.
        
        BOSTONS NEW SUBWAY FOUR-TRACK SUBWAY UNDER TRKMONT-ST.
        Inches across, ?ere encountered at that very in
        invenlent level, It became necessary to con
        utru t siphons, bending down under the subway
        and up agiln on the other Bide, in order to ad
        ju-t these conflicts of Interest.
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-08-17/ed-1/seq-63/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
    <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-admin-abraham-lincoln-assassination/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1865-04-15/ed-1/seq-1/#words=assassin+ASSASSINATION+PRESIDENT+President/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
    <text>M&jo" General, Com'd'g Department.
        general grant advised of pres
        1DENT LINCOLN'S ASSASSINATION.
        Philadelphia, April 11.?General Grant
        received the news of the attempted assassina
        tionof the President when at Walnut street
        wharf, when about taking the cars for Bur
        lington.
        ASSOCIATED PRESS ACCOUNT.
        President Lincoln and wife, together with
        other friends, last evening visited Ford
        Theater for the purpose of witnessing the per
        formance of the American Cousin. It was
        announced in the newspapers that Gen. Grant
        would also be present, but that gentleman, in
        stead, toek the late train of cars for New Jer
        sey. The theater was densely crowded, and
        everybody seemed delighted with the scene
        before them.
        Dnring the third act, and while there was
        temporary pause for one of the actors to enter,
        a sharp report of a pistol was heard, which
        merely attracted attention, but suggesting no
        thing serious until & ro&n rushed to tlie front
        of the President's box, waiving a long dagger
        in bis right hand, and exclaiming "Sic Semper
        Twannis," and immediately leaped from the
        box, which was of the second tier, to the stage
        beneath, and ran across to the opposite side
        thus making his escape, amid the bewilder
        ment of the audience, from the rear of the
        theater, and, mounting a horse, fled.
        The-ecreamt of Mrs. Lincoln first disclosed
        the feet to the audience that the President had
        been shot, when all present rose to their feet,
        rushing toward the stage, exclaiming, "Hang
        him!" "Hang him!''
        The excitement was of the wildest possible
        character, and, of course, there was an abrupt
        termination of the theatrical performance.
        Tbsi-e wis a rush towards the PretHtonf*
        bo*, when cries were heard. "Stand back'"
        "Give him air!" "Has anyone stimulants!"
        Ac.
        On a hasty examination it w&6 found that
        the President had been shot through the head,
        above and back of the temporal bone, and that
        some of ihe brain was oozing out. He was re
        moved to the private residenoe of Mr. Peterson,
        opposite to the theater, and the Surgeon Gene
        ral of the Army and other surgeons sent for to
        attend to hie condition.
        
        ASSASSINATION OF
        THE PRESIDENT.
        ATTEMPTED MURDER OF SECRE
        TARY SEWARD AND SONS.
        Despatches from Secretary Stanton.
        War Department, )
        WASHINGTON, D. C., AprH 15?1.30 P. M. $
        Major General JlAh A. Dix, Siw York:
        Last eTening, at 10.30 p. m., at Ford's Thea
        ter, the President, while sitting in bis private
        box with Mrs. Lincoln, Miss Harris, and Maj.
        Rathbun, was shot by an assassin who scd
        denly entered the box. He approached behind
        the President. The assassin then leaped npon
        the stage, brandishing a iarge dagger or knife,
        and made his escape by the rear of the theater.
        The pistol ball entered the back of the Presi
        dent's head. The wound is mortal. The Presi
        dent has been insensible ever since It wa9 in
        flicted, and is now dying.
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016836/1865-04-20/ed-1/seq-2/#words=dead+DEAD+LINCOLN/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
    <text>ABRAHAM LINCOLN IS DEAD
        On Sabbath morning the terriblj
        news fell upon us—crushing, stupefy
        ing, sickening. Men heard with
        blanched cheeks, and the blood cold—*
        irozen—in their veins. To believ
        seemed impossible, and yet there wa:
        no rojm for hope—the truth was only
        too well established. Words were pow
        erless'. In the formation of language
        no such deed as this—the assassination
        of Liberty's chosen son in a land that
        boasted to breathe only the air of free
        dom—had never been contemplated,
        and the brain of man had framed noth
        ing for the tongue to express that was
        not viak and impotent. So, with
        hearts sick and tears brimming over
        from eyes that were only then willing,
        they turned their steps to the house of
        that God whose "ways are inscrutable
        and past, finding out," or returned
        wearily to darkened homes—the bright
        ness of the holy day seeming in mock
        ery of the black pall that uhrouded all
        within.
        On Friday night, of last week an
        nrmed assassin entered the private.box
        at a theatre in Washington occupied by
        the President and his family, and ap
        proaching him from behind, sent
        cowardly bullet to smite the brain of
        the innocent, unsuspecting, great man,
        and doits work of death. Leaping to
        the stage, he escaped from the.theatre
        —leaving his victim passing insensibly
        from life to death.
        Oh I it is too terrible—too hea
        ickening!
        Such assassination would strike hor
        ror to the soul of every man not steep
        ed to fullest saturation in the poison of
        disloyalty, because the victim was the
        President of the United States the
        chosen ruler of the peoplu the embod
        iment of the laws, the jastiee, the hon
        or of his country. Thus it would shock
        him as a citizen. But more was the
        sorrow ot those "who loved him as
        ABRAHAM LINCOLN—-the father of his
        people—-almost' as children
        father of their home. The heart of th
        nation had twined around, that great
        body and taken it to themselves, and
        the great soul it contained had become
        a part of their soul and the bullei
        every fiber in this net-work' of love wo
        ven Ttj the people uhtil ty quivered in
        agony. He had' given a life-time of
        earnest and successful endeavor to their
        cause, and they, were not. stinting in
        their reward, infinitely precious, foi
        its sincerity.
        
        Last evening about 9:30 P. M., ai
        Pord's theatre, the President, while
        tting in his private- box with Mre.
        Lincoln, Mrs. Rodgers and Major Rath
        burn, was shot by an assassin, who sud
        lenly entered the box and approached
        ithind the President bm
        The assassin then escaped upon the
        stagfl brandishing a- large dagger
        The recovery of. Fred SeW
        OB doubtful!
        hut finished, and to see. the people of
        his nation gathered under the growing i»f no* probable that the President
        branches of the tree of Peace^-whosc fffl
        
        WAR DKPABTMBHT,
        Washington, April 16, 8 i. M.
        Official notice of the death of the
        late President, Abraham Lincoln, was
        given by the head of this Department
        lumped from the, box as before stated. :,. •«.!
        I •this morning to Andrew Johnson, Vice
        As the assassin ran across the stage]
        Col. J. B. Stewart, of this eityf'who
        was occupying one of the front seats in
        the. OT chestra, on the same side of th«
        house as the one occupied by. r. Lin'
        coin, sprung to the stage and followed
        ijm, but he was obstructed in his pas
        sage across the stage by the fright oi
        ne of the actors, and reached the back
    </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-panama-canal/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024546/1889-01-03/ed-1/seq-4/#words=Canal+canal+Lesseps+Panama+de+France+PANAM/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Panama Canal will, we believe, be cut,
        because it is wanted, because it bas tired the
        imagination of two continents, and because,
        though it may never pay the cutters, it will pay
        certain other powerful men; hut it will never
        be cnt by M. de Lesseps and bis present com
        pany. Those who'still believe that because M
        de Lasseps finished the Suez Canal, therefore
        he must, m spite of all appearances, finish tbe
        Panama Canal, forget the dominant facts of
        the situation. Tbe money subscribed, which
        has been really about 55,000,000, though the
        nominal sum advanced has been nearer
        75.000,000, has all been expended, and
        until tbe canal is completely finished,
        and for heavy ships, that enormous sum, ex
        ceeding the capital of 50 first-class banks, is
        all unproductive money, yielding no more than
        if it had been literally buried in the swamps of
        tbeChagres. To finish the canal will take, by
        the best calculations, forty millions sterling
        more. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1914-08-15/ed-1/seq-14/#words=CANAL+canal+PANAMA+Panama+Canal/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ANC?N OFFICIALLY OPENS
        PANAMA CANAL TO-DAY
        10.000 Ton Steamship Will Take Colonel Goethals and
        President of Panama and His Cabinet Through Water?
        way?Despite the Water It Will Be a "Dry" Trip.
        Panama, Aug. U. The Panama Cana
        wa? the seen" of activity to-night ir
        preparation for its opening to-morrow</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
